Rajneesh Gadge

Flat 114, Jay Ambey Apartment, DDA LIG Flats, New Kondli, Mayur Vihar - 3, New Delhi 96

+91-9718 612 440

■ rajneeshgadge17@gmail.com ■ DOB: 16th April, 1984

System Engineer

Accomplished IT professional with demonstrated success, Technology savvy self-starter, adept at moving into new environments and extrapolate from existing experience to quickly adapt to new technologies fluently. Possess first-rate communications and collaboration skills to lead and work in concert with diverse groups effectively.

Experience

Currently working with iGATE Global Solutions Limited a.k.a Cappemini - 139, 140, Noida Special Economic Zone (NSEZ), Noida – 201305.

System Engineer, Dec 2013 to Present.

- Monitor Linux boxes and hardware resources using Nagios X.
- Handling day to day system administration tasks related to user administration on Linux Servers which involves, Managing groups and user accounts, assign permissions to users.
- Responsible for installation and troubleshooting remote system for webservers (Apache).
- Installing, Managing and upgrading patches and packages.
- Configuring the private repository for accessing the packages with YUM.
- Experience on file system and disk management and managing disk quotas.
- Creating and managing user accounts, groups and access levels using SUDO.
- Configuring the LVMs and adding the additional disk space as and when required.
- Managing NFS in client-server architecture with Auto mount Autofs.
- Installing and Configuration of Open SSH, Scheduling/Controlling of jobs using cron and at.
- Implementing ACL's& special file permissions for security purpose.
- Configuring the network services like FTP, NFS.
- Managing Nagios alerts, adding new clients to Nagios, enabling and stopping manged services and decommissioning old hosts from nagios.

Arvato Bertelsmann – 15th Floor, Tower C, Bldg. No. 8, DLF Cyber City, Gurgaon *Technical Support Engineer - Enterprise*, Nov 2011 to Oct 2013.

- · Communication with customers over phone
- Remote assistance to customers using Remote Desktop, WebEx or, Team Viewer alike
- Working with team leader to introduce amendments into user guides
- Working with product managers to identify new features for development
- Fulfill IT security issues, follow corporate security standards and requirements
- Provide service and support for corporate and home users and holding introductions to new users
- Explain detailed technical aspects/solutions to customers and partners (resellers)
- · Help customers identify their issues, needs and requirements
- Deliver a world-class customer experience
- Enable customers to be successful with Client products and services
- Drive customer loyalty through value-added service
- Ability to demonstrate empathy to a customer situation
- Able to solve customer queries
- Set customer expectations appropriately
- Ability to question logically and effectively to identify the root cause of a problem

Server Techonologies:

Nagios, squid, Apache, LDAP, NFS, Active Directory, DHCP/DNS.

Hardware Platform:

RHEL 7, RHEL 6, Windows 10, 8.1, 8, 7, Vista, XP, Windows Server 2012, 2008, R2, SBS 2012 R2, vmware ESXi, Hyper-V. RVG News Vision Pvt. Ltd. — Gurgaon, NCR. — Midsize media and database firm

Graphic & Web Designer, Oct 2009 to Oct 2011

NewsVision is committed to provide timely, relevant and useful information, knowledge and perspective in an efficient and user-friendly format to stakeholders in the retail, fashion and luxury industry.

Results:

- Responsible for the design and development HTML pages and newsletters through the use of Adobe Dreamweaver CS5, Adobe Photoshop CS5 and Adobe Flash CS5.
- Developed page layout, navigation, copy, animation, buttons and icons.
- Presented designs and concepts to Clients and the Management for review.
- Assisted help desk staff in streamlining the process.
- Perform the validation and testing of the finished web sites.

Education

Graduate, BSc (IT) SMU DE, 2013. 12th, CBSE, New Delhi, 2001 10th, CBSE, New Delhi, 1999.